Change your desires rather than the order of the world.
René Descartes, "Discourse on the Method"
Graduation Ceremony
Representing the graduating students,
Horikita Manabu of Class A.
Our reply.
On this day, when the fragrance of plum
conveys to us the first breath of spring,
we accomplished our graduation.
Three years ago, we entered
Advanced Nurturing High School,
Despite Nagumo's interference,
he maintained Class A.
and I clearly remember swearing to myself
that I would make sure these three
years would be worthwhile ones.
Through competition and hard work,
we survived the many special exams we faced,
and today, I am grateful to be
able to graduate with all of you.
The resolute efforts of those comrades
who are no longer with us, too,
were not in vain.
Their noble visages remain
inscribed deeply on our hearts.
I ensure you, here and now,
that what you learn at this school
will be a treasure for your future,
and will be of great use to you.
Those of you who currently have doubts
must continue to step forward without fear.
You must believe that when you do,
the world that seems cold and closed off
now will greet you with gentle warmth.
Next year, and the year after,
whoever is to stand here making
that graduate address—
you will surely have a moment
when you understand that.
Thank you sincerely for
these past three years.
Horikita Manabu, speaking on
behalf of the graduating class.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
Now, before tomorrow's end-of-term ceremony,
we'll have a simple review of this term.
I'll start by saying you performed admirably
against Class A in the final special exam.
It's a massive difference from how you were
when you first arrived here one year ago.
But, Sensei, we've fallen back to Class D.
Totally back to square one.
After all our hard work
making it to Class C...
Right?
You did fall to Class D, it's true.
But you have grown a tremendous
amount in this past year.
In terms of class points,
you gained the most out of everyone.
It's kinda scary when
you praise us that much.
This isn't leading to a catch, is it?
It is not.
But the other classes have grown, as well.
Whether or not you're able to
surpass them in the days to come
will be determined by whether or not
you can maintain your hard work.
The graduation party will be today,
but although there is no class today,
do not forget that it is still a school day.
It sounds like you struggled
with the final exam.
I think Ryuen-kun's strategy
totally got in my head.
The result is that Class B lost badly.
I hear a lot of students
suddenly called out sick.
Yeah.
It was clearly a trap set by Ryuen-kun.
Final Special Exam
But the greatest cause of our defeat
was my inability to make
a psychological comeback
as the captain.
Round 6
Judo
Yamada Albert
Select who will participate.
Selecting
Judo
Forfeit
It's unlikely to work, but shouldn't
you complain to the school staff?
I want to take this forward, as a lesson.
What do you mean?
If this had happened during a crucial
moment in our second or third years,
it could have been disastrous.
But in this moment, we can handle it.
I see.
Then there's no need for an outsider
like me to poke my nose in.
I hear you guys put up a really good fight.
You're really getting better and better.
I guess we'd better watch our backs!
On that subject...
To be blunt, I'd like to dissolve
our alliance moving into next year.
Yeah, I had a feeling you might say that.
But...
I wonder if we could preserve
it for now, at least.
Maybe once the gap in our
class points gets tighter—
No.
My goal for next year is to
become Class B or higher.
And in order to overtake Class A,
I intend to go after points, as well.
You're serious about this, huh?
I'm grateful to you for
bringing the alliance proposal to us
back when we were hopeless.
But next year we'll be genuine enemies, huh?
Class B will be giving all we have, too.
Good.
Are you going to the graduation party?
If you're asking whether I'm going
to see my brother, I don't plan to.
I thought you'd finally found
it in yourself to speak to him.
How is any of that your business?
I'm going to go see him.
Is that an issue for you?
No.
You're free to see my brother if you want to.
But first...
I suppose I'll do what I ought to do.
I'm on suspension for
allegations of impropriety.
I don't think I have the power to
stop Acting Chairman Tsukishiro.
If I act directly against his plans,
it could end up spreading the
chaos through the entire school.
Are you saying you want a sponsor
who can actively oppose him?
Mr. Mashima may be the ticket, then.
The school is full of surveillance cameras.
Leave the setting for the discussion to me.
Thank you very much.
Well, then—
Can I ask you one final question?
Yes.
You came to this school
hoping for a normal life.
Have you thought about what
will happen when you graduate?
My destiny is set in stone.
After I graduate, I'll go
back to where I came from,
and act as a mentor there, I'm sure.
So you're also here despite an
acceptance of your eventual fate?
It's all the more reason why I intend
to protect these three years I have.
I hope this school will be a positive
experience you'll carry with you all your life.
Reception Room
I'm coming in.
A directive from Chairman
Sakayanagi and a secret meeting
just before the graduation party.
Whatever this is, it must be rather important.
This is a rather reckless thing you've done.
I thought you wanted to live a peaceful life?
I have something important to discuss
regarding Chairman Tsukishiro.
What are you talking about?
Chairman Sakayanagi's suspension and
the results of the final special exam...
What if I were to tell you Chairman
Tsukishiro set them all up himself?
I'm not entirely convinced of your story,
but if it's true, it's not
something we can let slide.
But Mr. Mashima, just this
morning he gave you a pay cut
for breaking the rules of
the final special exam.
A pay cut for breaking the rules?
For the judo competition
between Class B and Class D,
the student chosen by
Class D was Yamada Albert.
I see.
That could have been a dangerous
match, had it gone through.
So Mr. Mashima used his
judgment to dub it a forfeit.
The acting chairman didn't
like that, I suppose.
He doesn't like the teachers
using their discretion, I guess?
If I think a situation's dangerous
to the students, I'll stop it.
If their behavior is wrong, I'll correct it.
Teachers have to be able
to protect their students!
It appears he can't be stopped.
If Mr. Mashima agrees to this,
then I'll help you, as well.
It sounds like we have an agreement.
I intend to take your side for
now as well, Ayanokoji-kun.
Only until the acting
chairman is gone, of course.
If he ever gets in the way of Class A,
I'll brutally slap him down.
I see.
The graduation party will begin soon.
You students should leave first.
We'll leave separately later.
Honestly.
He's brought a difficult
problem to our doorstep.
You really think taking out
Acting Chairman Tsukishiro will end it?
What do you mean?
There's no guarantee they won't
send another assassin after him.
If that were to happen, it could spread
beyond Ayanokoji's individual problem,
and affect the whole class year...
maybe even the entire school.
It's truly a quagmire.
I guess we should just hope
my worst fear won't come true.
I suppose.
3rd Season
Classroom
of
the
Elite
Classroom of
the Elite
I thought you'd be here.
Well? Is that a problem?
I was thinking.
The way you were before,
you probably wouldn't have come.
You think so?
I'm still me. I haven't changed at all.
Even if you don't graduate in Class A,
it must feel nice to graduate.
Even if you don't get a
shortcut to your dream,
maybe you can still carve a
path under your own power.
You should go.
Use your special privilege as little sister.
H-Hey!
For me to run to my brother's side now...
It feels unnatural.
Rather... it feels inappropriate.
I'm not chickening out.
I wanted to see my brother's
three years here.
That's why I came.
I'm leaving.
I've done what I came here to do.
What about you?
I'm staying a little while longer.
Oh?
Goodbye, then.
Were you waiting for me?
I thought this might be my
last chance to talk to you.
It seems Suzune has left.
She said she wanted to get a
look at your three years here.
Sorry. Maybe I should have done
more on the student council thing.
I have a favor to ask of you.
I'm leaving the school on the 31st.
Tell Suzune to meet me by the
front gate at noon that day.
Shouldn't you tell her yourself?
I want you to convince her.
There's a chance she might
not be honest with herself.
Today is my brother's last day at school.
I wasn't able to show
him my growth this year.
Is it all right for us to part like this?
Right now, I'm still the foolish little sister
who just chased after her big brother.
A fake...
I'm a fake.
What I really wanted my brother to see was...
Thank you.
To the fake
and the unquestionably real me.
I'm afraid your sister isn't here yet.
I see.
Ayanokoji, why are you
hiding your own talent?
I just don't like standing out, I guess.
Do you think living your school life
under the radar is really worthwhile?
You came to this school to make
some kind of mark, didn't you?
Make a mark?
I think that's something only
shining people like you can do.
If you can't make your
mark on the school itself,
you can make it on the students.
If you engrave on the minds of
the students that a student
named Ayanokoji Kiyotaka was here,
I don't think they'll forget
it all their lives.
I'm grateful for what
you've done for my sister.
But I've realized I'm the kind of
man who expects more than that.
That is why
I don't want you disappointing me.
I'll think about it.
That's all I ask.
The answer you find will guide you.
I should be going now.
I'm sorry to cause you trouble
right up until the end.
Are you sure you shouldn't call
your sister one last time?
No, a moment of inappropriate emotion
from me might inhibit her growth.
Forgive me for pushing it on you,
but I will leave Suzune in your care.
Let us meet again, Ayanokoji.
Brother!
I'm sorry I'm late.
You seem to have changed.
Rather... you've returned to the
person you were then, Suzune.
It took me a year...
No, many years.
I want to keep on walking forward,
for the sake of my classmates.
And in order to find my own path,
I'm going to keep learning
alongside my classmates.
It sounds like you really have returned
to the person you used to be.
Do you know my primary reason
for pushing you away?
No.
You were caught up in the illusion of me.
I simply couldn't allow that.
But you'll be all right.
I'm sure of that now.
Be strong with others, and also kind.
I will.
I must also apologize.
I lied back then, when I
said I preferred long hair.
You always liked having short hair,
so I lied to see if you'd
take it seriously or not.
Forgive me.
I forgive you.
I think your lie is the
reason I'm here right now.
Suzune, I care about you greatly.
Brother...
I'll be waiting for you outside
this gate in two years.
Show me how much you've grown.
I will. I'll do all I can
and fight to the bitter end.
Let us meet again.
Yes.